# Hope K. Snyder

1133 Ashland Road #1407, Columbia, MO 65201 (814) 969-1082 (cell)

hks2010@hotmail.com (personal) | hks7w2@mail.missouri.edu (student)

# **Objective**

Data scientist with 6+ years of experience in psychological data analysis and general data analytics. Co-founder of Code-RLadies (the mid-Missouri chapter of RLadies). Skilled in statistics, problem solving, R programming, and GIT integration. Interest in big data technologies, cloud computing, and database software.

# **Skills & Abilities**

#### **QUANTITATIVE SKILLS**

· Probability Theory

· Statistical Theory

· Bayesian Data Analysis

· Item Response Modeling

· Categorical Data Analysis

· Multilevel Modeling

 Multivariate Predictive Modeling · Multilevel Calculus

· Real Analysis

#### RESEARCH SKILLS

 Experimental Design and Programming · Data Analysis

· Data Visualization Tools

Machine Learning
 Techniques

#### **SOFTWARE KNOWLEDGE**

 R statistical software (Studio, Shiny, and Markdown, Tidyverse)

 $\cdot$  GIT and GitHub

· JAGS

· SPSS

· SAS

LaTeX

MATLab (Octave)

· AWS EC2 instances

(minimal)

Microsoft Office programs:
 Word, Excel, PowerPoint

#### TRADITIONAL SKILLS

Interpersonal Skills

Verbal and Written
 Communication

Perceptive

· Critical Thinking

· Active Learning

· Time-Management Skills

#### **Education**

# UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI | PRESENT | DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY IN QUANTITATIVE PSYCHOLOGY

· Advisor: Clintin Davis-Stober, PhD

#### UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI | 2018 | MASTER OF ARTS IN PSYCHOLOGY

- · Thesis: A Bayesian Investigation into Inhibition Mechanisms of Contrast and Assimilation
- · Advisor: Jeffrey N. Rouder, PhD.
- · GPA: 3.938

#### WASHINGTON & JEFFERSON COLLEGE | 2014 | BACHELOR OF ARTS

- · Major: Mathematics and Psychology
- · GPA: 3.82; Magna Cum Laude, 26th of 307; Beta Scholar
- · Honors Societies: Alpha Lambda Delta, Pi Gamma Mu, Pi Mu Epsilon, Psi Chi, Phi Beta Kappa
- · Activities: Math Club Treasurer, W&J Chapter of Pi Mu Epsilon Vice President, Wind Ensemble Member

### GIRARD HIGH SCHOOL | 2010 | HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA

- · Honors Course of Study, Third in Class, GPA: 4.13
- · Activities: Marching Band, Concert Band, Show Choir, Bell Choir, Theater—Nine productions

# **Experience**

### JUNIOR DATA SCIENTIST | CARFAX, INC. | 5/2019 — 8/2019, 1/2020 — 3/2020

- · Leverage data science to increase revenue and decrease expenses
- · Developed a geospatial web application to visualize fraud and identify new business leads
- · Demonstrated business value of cloud computing (e.g. Azure) and data science platforms
- · Developed optimized software in R to increase productivity of colleagues
- · Communicated complex analyses and results to nontechnical audiences
- · Developed prototype machine learning model to analyze customer retention
- · Part of model building team for determining customer cost for business team in Canada

#### TEACHING ASSISTANT | UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI | 8/2018 — PRESENT

- · Worked with students on individual and small group basis to reinforce learning
- · Taught SPSS and R statistical software and provided technical support to students
- · Mentored advanced students on individual projects

#### RESEARCH ASSISTANT | UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI | 8/2016 — PRESENT

- · Researched constructs such as perception, attention and decision making
- · Implemented Bayesian mathematical models to analyze data
- · Programmed experimental trials and stimulus in Octave (MATLab).
- · Received funding from University of Missouri Graduate School and Psychology department

#### ASSISTANT WEBSITE DESIGNER | W.I.S.E. CLAREMONT COLLEGES | 9/2014 — 6/2015

- · Transferred materials into new layout within WordPress jointly with a group
- · Updated format to improve user experience
- · Corrected and updated prior information about statistical measures
- · http://wise.cgu.edu

#### RESEARCH ASSISTANT | KENT STATE UNIVERSITY | 6/2013 — 8/2013

· Researched mathematical polynomial models to predict the maximum value

- Developed a program to estimate multiple predictive models in Java and instructed others through development of the program
- · Received funding from Kent State University Mathematics department

# RESEARCH ASSISTANT | WASHINGTON & JEFFERSON COLLEGE | 6/2012-8/2012

- · Researched mathematical theory behind familiar geometric shapes under different distance measurements
- Received funding from Mathematics Association of America and Washington & Jefferson Mathematics department

#### **Publications**

- Davis-Stober, C. P., Snyder, H. K., Park, S., and Regenwetter, M. (2019) Cognitive Aging and Tests of Rationality. <u>DOI</u>
- · Snyder, H. K., Rafferty, S. M., Haaf, J. M., & Rouder, J. N. (2019). Common or distinct attention mechanisms for contrast and assimilation? *Attention, Perception, & Psychophysics*, 1-7. GitHub
- · Rouder, J. N., Haaf, J. M., & Snyder, H. K. (2019). Minimizing mistakes in psychological science. *Advances in Methods and Practices in Psychological Science*, *2*(1), 3-11. <u>PsyArXiv GitHub</u>
- · Haaf, J. M., Rhodes, S., Sun, T. K., Snyder, H. K., Naveh-Benjamin, M., & Rouder, J. (2018). Revisiting the remember-know task: Replications of Gardiner and Java (1990). <a href="PsyArXiv">PsyArXiv</a>

#### **Presentations**

- · Snyder H. K. (2020) Building a Technical Toolkit: Some Helpful R Packages. Talk presented at the Quantitative Seminar at the University of Missouri, Columbia, MO.
- · Snyder, H. K. & Landon, L. (2020). An Introduction to RStudio: How to Navigate and Useful Tips. Talk presented at Code-RLadies February meeting, Columbia, MO.
- · Snyder, H. K. & Fitzsimmons, E. (2020). Getting R Installed and Working. Talk presented at Code-RLadies January meeting, Columbia, MO.
- Snyder, H. K. & Engelhardt, C. R. (2019). A Game of Clue: Fraud Detection An Application to Identify Product Misuse and Business Leads. Talk presented at the Fourth Annual Carfax Tech Summit, Columbia, MO.
- · Snyder, H. K. (2019). Binary Decision-Making Process Over Time: Exploring the Diffusion Model. Talk presented at the Quantitative Seminar at the University of Missouri, Columbia, MO
- Snyder, H. K. (2018). A Bayesian Investigation into Inhibition Mechanisms of Contrast and Assimilation.
  Talk presented at the Fifth Summer School of Computational and Mathematical Modeling of Cognition,
  Couches, France.
- Snyder, H. K. & Rouder, J. N. (2018). A Bayesian Investigation into Inhibition Mechanisms of Contrast and Assimilation. Poster presented at the Fifth Summer School of Computational and Mathematical Modeling of Cognition, Couches, France.
- · Snyder, H. K. (2018). A Bayesian Investigation into Inhibition Mechanisms of Contrast and Assimilation. Talk presented at the Quantitative Seminar at the University of Missouri, Columbia, MO

- · Snyder, H. K., Rafferty, S. M., Haaf, J. M., and Rouder, J. N. (2017). Common or distinct attention mechanisms for contrast and assimilation? Poster presented at the Psychonomic Society 58<sup>th</sup> Annual Meeting, Vancouver, Canada.
- · Snyder, H. K. (2017). Finding the Forest Through the Trees: A Bayesian Analysis of Flanker Effects on Perceptions. Talk presented at the Quantitative Seminar at the University of Missouri, Columbia, MO.
- · Snyder, H. K., Klein, D., Cartor, R., Carleton, R. and Tonge, A. (2014). How Low can you go? Estimating the Maximum of a Polynomial. Talk presented at the Joint Mathematics Meeting, Baltimore, MD.
- · Snyder, H. K. & Wong, R. (2013). Conics in Extended Taxicab Geometry. Talk presented at the National Conference for Undergraduate Research, La Crosse, WI.
- · Snyder, H. K. & Wong, R. (2013). Conics in Extended Taxicab Geometry. Talk presented at the Joint Mathematics Meeting, San Diego, CA.
- · Snyder, H. K. (2012). Conics in Taxicab Geometry and Extended Taxicab Geometry. Talk presented at the Mathematics Association of America's Mathfest, Madison, WI.
  - o Outstanding Presentation Award

### **Awards**

- Robert S. Daniel Graduate Teaching Fellowship (Since 08/2018). Department of Psychological Sciences, University of Missouri.
- G. Ellsworth Huggins Scholarship (Since 08/2016). 3-year Doctoral Level Fellowship awarded by the Office of Graduate Studies, University of Missouri.
- Graduate Student Travel Grant for attending the Psychonomic Society 58<sup>th</sup> Annual Meeting (2017). Department of Psychological Sciences, University of Missouri.
- · Scholar of Psychology Award (2014). Department of Psychology, Washington & Jefferson College.
- · Clyde Shepherd Atchison Scholar Book Award (2014). Department of Mathematics, Washington & Jefferson College.
- · Dr. Mariano Garcia '39 Award in Mathematics (2014). Department of Mathematics, Washington & Jefferson College.
- · Dr. Mariano Garcia '39 Award in Mathematics (2013). Department of Mathematics, Washington & Jefferson College.
- Howard J. Burnett Presidential Scholarship (2010). Awarded by the Office of Admission, Washington & Jefferson College.

#### References

#### DR. JENNY KLINE | PROFESSOR OF MATHEMATICS | WASHINGTON & JEFFERSON COLLEGE

- · 724-503-1001, Ext. 6176
- · jkline@washjeff.edu

# DR. ROMAN WONG || PROFESSOR OF MATHEMATICS | WASHINGTON & JEFFERSON COLLEGE

- · 724-503-1001, Ext. 6180
- · rwong@washjeff.edu

# DR. TIMOTHY KLITZ || PROFESSOR OF PSYCHOLOGY | WASHINGTON & JEFFERSON COLLEGE

- · 724-503-1001, Ext. 3357
- · tklitz@washjeff.edu

# DR. JEFF ROUDER || PROFESSOR OF PSYCHOLOGY | UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA-IRVINE

· <u>jrouder@uci.edu</u>

### DR. CLINTIN DAVIS-STOBER || PROFESSOR OF PSYCHOLOGY | UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI

· stoberc@missouri.edu

# DR. CHRIS ENGELHARDT || LEAD DATA SCIENTIST | CARFAX, INC. || CEO | TABASTATS ANALYTICS

- · 814-449-7762
- · Cre8f9@mail.missouri.edu